菲比，帮我挑订婚戒指好吗？ 我觉得好难挑喔
Can you help me pick an engagement ring?I can't figure this out.
我要选蒂凡尼切割法还是… 公主方切割法还是…
Should I get her a Tiffany cut or a princess cut or a..?
被纸切割法
Paper cut!
你有告诉其他人吗？
-Have you told anyone else?
没有，我不想让莫妮卡发现
-No,I don't want Monica to find out.
可是你告诉我了
You told me.
因为我信任你 你是我的好朋友
Because I trust you and we're friends...
而且你在我看戒指目录时闯进来
and you saw me looking at ring brochures.
进房不敲门再次大有收获
Once again,not knocking pays off.
只要你不是在厕所就好了 我有同感
-I wish you hadn't been on the toilet. -Me too.
我看看，有莫妮卡切割法吗？ 有的话就是它了
Let me see. Is there such a thing as a Monica cut?Because that would be you best bet.
钱德，要不要去喝咖啡？
-Want to go to the coffeehouse?
好啊 走吧
-Oh,all right.
太好了，我们正想找你们下去
We were just gonna see if you wanted to go.
不要，我们要去别的地方
Well,we don't because we got the other place.
真没礼貌
How rude.
抱歉，你要吃吗？
Sorry. Want a bite?
本集播出：“完美的戒指”
The One With The Ring
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
你和保罗交往得怎样？
So how are things going with Paul?
很好
Good.
只不过他很内敛
Although,you know,he's a private guy.
真想让他稍微敞开心胸 分享心情
I wish I could get him to open up,share some feelings.
简单 把他想成打不开的罐子就对了
You just have to think of him as a jar of pickles that won't open.
你要我捉他的头冲热水敲桌子
I should run him under hot water and bang his head against a table?
不是，那是拷问的手法
That's what you do when you want to get the truth out of someone.
亲爱的
Hello honey
看我的 好
-Watch this. -Okay.
保罗  菲比
-Hey,Paul. -Hi,Phoebe.
你最近好吗？
How are things going with you?
没得抱怨
Can't complain.
嘿  嗨
-Hey! -Hi.
我也很高兴见到你，我很好
-Great to.. -Ross,good to see you too.
保重
You take care.
你们刚才为什么见到我们就跑
What was the deal with you and Chandler blowing us off before?
很怪吧？
That was so weird,huh?
菲比，为什么？
Why did you do it?
不是我，是钱德
I didn't do it. It was Chandler.
他…他在生你们的气
He's mad at you.
为什么？ 拜托，你明知故问
-What? Why? -Oh,please. I think you know why.
我想不起来
I can't think of anything.
罗斯，你是古生物学家 再往深处去挖
Come on. You're a paleontologist. Dig a little deeper.
等等，是不是因为两个星期前 乔伊和我没找他去看尼克队的比赛？
Is it because Joey and I didn't invite him to that Knicks game?
你觉得他会为这种事生气吗？
Is that something he'd be mad at you for?
应该会 我想就是这个原因
-I guess it could. -Well,then I think that's it.
他不该隐瞒他的情绪 他应该老实告诉我
If he's angry,he shouldn't hide it. I wish he'd just tell me the truth.
那你应该捉他的头 去冲热水敲桌子
You should run him under hot water and bang his head against the table.
我在“中国花园”订了位 可以吗？
Honey,I made a reservation at China Garden. Is that okay?
可以啊，很棒
Yeah,that's great.
但你先跟我说说话 说说你今天好不好
But first,talk to me. Talk to me. Tell me about your day.
蛮好的
It was fine.
好吧
Okay.
你在想什么？你现在在想什么
What are you thinking right now?
我在想你穿这件裙子很好看
That you are looking really fine in that dress.
太好了，但是…
Yeah,that's great,Paul. But,you know....
我想知道…哇，好结实
I want to know what.. Wow,those are really great!
我想知道这坚强沉默的外表下 隐藏着什么
I just want to know...what is behind this strong,silent exterior?
俗语说静水深流 我想在你的心中畅游
They say that still waters run deep,and I want to swim in yours.
你在讲做爱的事吗？
Are you talking about having sex?
不是的，保罗，我一点也不了解你
No,Paul.I don't know anything about you.
例如你的童年，聊聊你的童年
Tell me about your childhood.
很普通
Normal.
好，那青春期呢？ 青春期总是很讨厌
Then how about puberty? Come on! That's always a painful time.
朋友找你参加聚会
Your friends have a slumber party
趁你睡着把你的手放进热水里 害你在睡袋里撒尿
and stick your hand in warm water...while you sleep,so you pee in your sleeping bag.
我没碰过那种事
No,that never happened to me.
那是你走运 没碰上那个贱人莎朗麦杰斯基
You're lucky you never met that bitch,Sharon Majeski.
总之… 其他时期有什么悔恨吗？
Anyway...The rest of your life. Any regrets?
没有
Nope.
保罗，我要求得不多
I'm not asking for a lot here.
你就讲一件事，什么事都好
Just give me something. Anything.
好吧
-Okay. -Okay.
6岁那年 我想要一辆大脚踏车
When I was 6 years old,I wanted a Big Wheel.
我父母却送我一个 小鸡造型的跳跳乐
And instead,my parents got me this little...plastic chicken that you hop around on.
太难为情了，其他小孩子都笑我
It was embarrassing. Kids made fun of me.
那一年蛮痛苦的
That was a tough year.
太好了，你看吧 我觉得我比较了解你了，谢谢
That's great! See?I already feel like I know you a little better.
好，我们去吃饭吧
Okay,come on. Now we can go eat. Let's go!
我好惨
It was horrible.
大家都叫我小鸡鸡
They called me "Chicken Boy."
五年级我跟别人打架 其实也不算打架
In fifth grade,I got in a fight. Well,not really.
理查达伦咬我的鼻子，我摔倒
Richard Danville bit me on the nose and，and I feel down
这里留了一个小伤疤，你看  对对对，我看见了
I still have a little scar right here. You can see it.Yeah,yeah. I see the scar.
保罗，你听我说 你这样分享你的心情真的很棒
I think this is really great that,you know,you've shared your feelings.It's really... It's beautiful.
但是我们现在去吃饭吧
But what do you say we go share some food?
我现在吃不下
No,I couldn't eat now.
你在说什么？ 你最爱吃宫保鸡丁了
What are you talking about? You love their Kung Pao chicken!
鸡？
Chicken?
小鸡鸡 天哪，对不起，我不是故意的
-Chicken Boy! -I'm sorry. I didn't mean to do that.
一无所获
Nothing
逛了几百家店 还是找不到完美的戒指
This is the nine millionth ring store,and I can't find the perfect ring.
丑，丑，丑
Ugly ring,ugly ring,ugly ring...
这些戒指真美
It's a beautiful selection.
要不然你不送戒指
So maybe you don't get her a ring.
送点不一样的
Maybe you do something different.
例如订婚手镯，或是订婚头饰
An engagement bracelet or an engagement tiara!
订婚独立战争毛瑟枪
An engagement Revolutionary War musket!
真高兴我是选你来帮忙
I'm so glad I picked you to help me with this.
你能不能想像你单膝跪下
Imagine getting down on one knee...
把这件漂亮的火器交给她？
and handing her this gorgeous piece of weaponry?
我还是送戒指好了
I'll stick with the ring.
这只好漂亮，我喜欢这只
This one's nice. I like it.
先生？好心的先生？我想看这枚戒指
Sir?Kind sir,can I see this one?
你找我来就是因为我会讲价
This is why you brought me. I know how to haggle.
所以接下来交给我处理
-Let me handle this from here.
有什么需要吗？
-Can I help you?
有，我想看那枚戒指
-I would like to see that ring.
或是不看，随便
-Or not. Whatever.
这是一只20年代的戒指 1.5克拉，两侧镶有蓝宝石
This ring is from the 1920s.It's a one and a half carat diamond with sapphires.
先生，你能不能…
Sir,could I ask you...?
拿着戒指向我求婚？
Could you hold out that ring and ask me to marry you?
好
-Okay. -Okay.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
天哪，就是它了
Oh,my God,that's it! That's the ring!
多少钱？ 钱德，让我来
-How much is it? -I will handle this.
多少钱？
How much is it?
$8600.
我们出10块钱
We will give you $10.
你到底想不想买？ 想，想，但我只能出8000
-Are you interested in this ring? -Yes.But I can only pay $8000.
好，8000可以 我们坚持10块钱
-Okay. I can let it go for 8. -We stand firm at $10.
你要怎么付帐？ 刷卡
-How would you like to pay? -Credit card.
不对，我的卡在乔伊那边
Oh,no! I lent my credit card to Joey.
我回去拿，你守住戒指
I'll go get it. You guard the ring.
你为什么把你的卡给乔伊？
-Why did you give your credit card to Joey?
他要买尼克队的球票 结果他这个混蛋居然没有找我一起去
-To buy some Knicks tickets.Then the jerk didn't even invite me to the game.
不过我已经不在意了
But I'm over it. Whatever!
刚才很抱歉
Listen,I'm sorry about before.
你们有10块钱的东西吗？
Do you have anything here for $10?
有，我有两张崭新的5元钞票
Yes. I have these two rather beautiful...five-dollar bills.
我出1块钱跟你买
I'll give you $1 for them.
昨天钱德和菲比 不是看到我们就跑了吗？
Remember how Chandler and Phoebe blew us off yesterday?
有吗？
No.
你当时在吃披萨
-Remember,you were eating pizza?
喔对 好
-Yeah.
钱德显然是在气我们2星期前 没帮他买球票
Chandler's angry at us for not getting him a ticket to that Knicks game.
我们为什么要帮他买票？
We were supposed to just get him one?
那家伙老是揩我们的油 就是啊
That guy's always mooching off of us.
但我还是觉得应该设法和解
Anyway,I still think we should try to patch things up.
我们可以找他去看另一场球赛
We could get tickets to another game and invite him.
好主意 而且他的卡还在我这里
That's a great idea. And I still have his credit card.
帐单
Here you go.
我有卡，拿去吧
Hey,hey. I got this one. Here you go.
有时候我真搞不懂钱德
Sometimes I just don't get Chandler.
我和他做很多事都没找你 你也不会生气
We do stuff all the time without you,and you don't get all upset.
很多事？ 可多了
-All the time? -All the time.
抱歉，这张卡不能刷
I'm sorry,it was rejected.
不可能，我看看
That's impossible. Let me see that.
这张是我的，拿去吧
This one's mine. Here you go.
我的天哪我的天哪
Oh,my God! Oh,my God!
还在哭？ 跟小女生一样
-Still crying? -Like a little girl.
我知道…都是我不好
I know,I know. This is all my fault.
是我要他敞开心胸的
I wanted him to open up.
但是我不知道我会放出一头 哭哭啼啼又粘人的怪物
I didn't know that I was gonna unleash...this weepy,clingy,moist monster!
有两个办法能让一个男人闭嘴
I only know of two ways to shut a man up.
其中一个办法是做爱
One of them is sex.
另一个是什么？ 不知道，我只用过第一个
-What's the other? -Don't know. Never had to use it.
我只是说做爱的时候 他就不能讲话
I'm just saying,if we're having sex,he's not talking.
没错，话多的是你
That's right. You're the talker.
总之这个主意很棒
Anyway,great idea.
我要去商店 我答应去帮他买面纸
I gotta buy him some more tissues.
我们这里有… 你们已经没有了
-We have some here. -No,you don't!
好，我还想试戴头饰
Okay. I'd also like to try on the tiara.
太好了
Oh,yeah. Okay.
怎么样？太过了吗？
What do you think? Too much?
有一点 好吧
A tad.
把头饰放回去
Take the tiara back...
毛瑟枪再给我一次
and let me hold the musket again.
少了点什么…
Something's missing.
把我朋友挑的戒指拿给我
Let me see the ring that my friend picked out.
那枚20年代的钻戒呢？
-Where's the 1920s princess-cut ring?
刚刚卖给那位先生
-I just sold it to that gentleman.
上帝啊
Oh,my God!
等等，别走
Wait,no!
放我出去，快点
Let me out! Now!
瑞秋…
Rachel?
不是
No.
保罗，你好吗？ 还好
-How are you,Paul? -Okay.
钱德…你爸抱过你吗？
Chandler...did your dad ever hug you?
没有，他抱过你吗？
-No. Did he hug you?
不是，只不过我爸都没抱过我
No! No.It's just that my dad never did.
我好想念我爸
I miss my dad.
你可以去拉斯维加斯 看我爸亲别人的爸爸
You can see my dad in Vegas kissing other dads.
钱德？ 怎样？
-Hey,Chandler? -Yeah?
你能不能…
Would you...?
你能不能抱我？
Would you hug me?
我有点忙
-I'm a little busy here,Paul.
我爸也都这么说
-That's what my dad used to say.
好啦，一下下，快点
Okay. A quick one. Come on,hug it out.
行了吧
There you go.
好了
Okay.
再5秒钟 够了
-Five more seconds.. -Okay!
乔伊  怎么了
-Joey! -What? Hey,what..?
保罗是吧？
Hi. Paul,is it?
我的信用卡在吗？ 在，在我的…
-Do you have my credit card? -Yeah. It's in my...
我的口袋里
In my pocket.
后面的口袋 幸好
-My back pocket! -Thank God.
我买了今天晚上尼克队的票
-I got tickets to the Knicks tonight.
我不能去 去啦，多好啊
-I can't go.It'll be fun.
我，你，罗斯和… 保罗吗？
Me,you,Ross and Paul,probably.
我没空好吗，我得走了
Look,I don't have time for this,okay? I gotta go.
好恶劣喔
That was mean.
就是啊
Yeah,I know.
过来吧 好
-Get in here. -Yeah.
钱德，我找到最完美的戒指了
Chandler,I found the perfect ring.
真不错 但我还是买之前那款好了
I'm gonna go with the one I picked first.
天哪，钱德，那枚戒指不在了
Oh,wake up. The one you picked is gone. It's over!
什么？
What?
被一个人买走了，对不起
Some guy bought it.
我想拦住他，却被关进监狱里
I tried to stop him,but they put me in jail!
被关进监狱里？ 门和门中间的小监狱
-They put you in jail? -The little jail between the doors!
菲比，我要你守着那枚戒指 我知道，对不起
-I asked you to guard the ring! -I know. I'm sorry.
但是这枚比较好 莫妮卡根本没看过另一枚
But this ring is better. And Monica never saw the other ring.
但是他用那枚戒指向我求婚时 我起了鸡皮疙瘩
Yeah,but when he proposed to me with the ring,I got goosebumps.
也许是因为那个人 是因为那枚戒指
-Maybe it was the guy. -It was the ring!
他知道票的事情兴奋吗？
-Was he excited about the tickets?
不，他回绝了
-No! He blew us off!
什么？ 就是啊
-What? -I know.
太不可思议了
I can't believe it.
告诉你，我现在有点生他气
Can I tell you something?I'm a little mad at him now!
告诉你
Can I tell you something?
我也是
Me too!
他生气不告诉我们
He didn't want to talk to us about being angry.
那我们也不要告诉他
Maybe we don't talk to him at all!
冷落他  没错
-Freeze him out. -Right!
我喜欢 给他好看
-I like it. -We'll show him.
以后就是乔伊与罗斯 最佳拍档
From now on,it's gonna be Joey and Ross,best friends.
我们将是新的乔伊与钱德
We'll be the new Joey and Chandler.
什么？ 你觉得你和钱德比我和钱德要好？
What?You think you and Chandler were closer than me and Chandler?
别生气
Hey,don't get angry.
我们一反目，他就赢了
We turn on each other,he wins.
我回来了
Hi,I'm back.
我把我想说的话都写下来了
I've written down more to tell you!
真好
Oh,that's great.
真是太好了，真的好棒
No,actually,that's...That's great. That's really great.
说真的，写东西会燃起…
You know,I gotta tell you,writing,all that writing,it gets me...
我的欲火
It gets me kind of hot.
等等，你听喔
Wait,wait. Listen to this:
你知道我小时候想当什么？
Know what I wanted to be at that age?
情圣？
A lover?
冲浪者 是吗？
-A surfer. -A surfer?
我想与海浪为伍
-I wanted to be one with the waves..
等等，等一下，让我把自己…
-Hold on.Let me just
弄得舒服一点
get a little more comfortable here.
等一下，这样会不会太露了？
Wait a second.This isn't too revealing,is it?
不会，当年那个小家伙呢？
No.Whatever happened to that little dude?
充满梦想…
So full of dreams.
我不在乎那个小家伙
I don't care about the little dude!
我听不下去了
I can't! I cannot listen to any more of this!
只有心理医师会想听这些话
The only one who'd listen is a mental health professional!
那还是因为他们1小时赚1百
That's only because they get $100 an hour!
你知道我听到现在可以赚多少
Do you know how much money I could have made listening to you?
2千块钱
$2000!
你知道我什么时候算出来的？ 在你唠叨的时候
Know when I figured that out? While you were talking!
你居然想扼杀我的情绪
I can't believe you're trying to stifle me
14个小时前我们才发现 那就是我妈的目的
when 14 hours ago...we figured out that's what my mother was trying to do!
对不起 我不是想扼杀你的情绪
I'm sorry.I don't mean... I didn't mean to stifle you.
我只是有点受不了
This is all just a little overwhelming.
瑞秋，对不起
I'm so sorry.
我不是故意的 只不过情绪一发泄
I didn't mean to overwhelm you.It's just that when those gates open...
就会…不可收拾
it's hard to close them.
不过现在没事了，真的
But they are closed now. Believe me.
我很高兴你跟我分享你的心情
I'm so glad. I'm so glad you shared.
也很高兴你分享完了
And I'm glad that you're done.
那我们要不要…
So what do you say we....
我求之不得
I'd like that.
真是…太棒了
That was so good!
我居然听你的话 买下这枚像口香糖一样的蠢戒指
I can't believe you talked me into this gumball-machine-looking ring.
它才不是口香糖蠢戒指，它很漂亮
It's not a gumball-machine-looking ring. It's a beautiful ring!
它才不漂亮
No,it's not.
另一枚戒指 会让我看到莫妮卡的表情
When I looked at the other ring,I could see Monica's face...
我会看到她点头答应
and I could see her saying yes.
这枚戒指只让我看到  一枚戒指
Looking at this,I only see a ring.
只有近看才会看到我的眼睛
Unless I look at it really closely,and then I can see my own eye.
这是我这辈子最重要的一件事 我想做到最完美
This is the most important thing I'll ever do. I want to make it perfect.
我们或许能把那枚戒指要回来
Maybe we could get the other ring back.
我听到那个人 准备求婚的地方
I heard where the guy was gonna propose.
或许我们可以说服他交换
-Maybe we could get him to trade rings.
我不能这么做
-I can't do that.
你总不能给她那枚口香糖蠢戒指
You certainly can't give her that stupid gumball ring.
好吧，他要去哪里？
-All right. Where was he going?
一家餐厅…彩虹什么的
-Yeah,it's a restaurant...The Rainbow something.
彩虹餐厅？ 不是
-Rainbow Room?
彩虹烧烤？ 不是
Rainbow Grill?
彩虹的彼端？ （电影“绿野仙踪”主题曲）
Somewhere Over the...?
空间
-L'Espace.
彩虹空间？ 不是，只有空间
-Rainbow L'Espace!No,just L'Espace.
我很乐意想知道你是怎么从彩虹想到空间的
I'd love to know how you got from rainbow to L'Espace.
你不会想知道的
No,you wouldn't.
我的思路很复杂
You don't wanna get in here.
就是他
There he is.
好，他还没求婚 因为她没有戴戒指
He hasn't proposed yet. She has no ring on.
你真行，我们应该去当侦探 没错
Wow,you're good! After this,we should solve crimes.
去请他过来 好
Okay. Go get him.Oh,okay.
抱歉，请您来一下 有您的电话
Excuse me. Could you come with me? You have a phone call.
是谁？ 是你的公司打来的
-Who is it? -It's your office.
你知道是谁吗？
-Do you know who at my office?
约翰？ 约翰啊，太好了
-John.Oh,John! Great!
他来了
-There he is.
你好，珠宝店搞错了
-Hi. Okay.There was a mix-up at the store.
他们把为我保留的戒指卖给你
The ring you have was supposed to be held for me.
所以我得跟你要回来
I'm gonna need to have that back.
不过我愿意拿这枚美丽的 更昂贵的戒指和你交换
In exchange,I'm willing to trade you this beautiful,more expensive ring.
要是我就换
Wow,I would trade.
的确很美，但是我要用这一枚
It is beautiful,but I'm gonna use this one.
失陪了
Excuse me.
不，这位是我的未婚妻 她就是要这枚戒指
This is my fiancee,and her heart was set on that ring.
你不会想伤她的心吧？
Do you want to break her heart?
对啊 你想伤一位垂死女人的心吗？
Yeah. Do you want to break a dying woman's heart?
你要死了？
You're dying?
她快死于…咳嗽了
Yeah,she's dying...of a cough,apparently.
对，我临死前想拥有那枚戒指
It's my dying wish to have that ring.
要是不能戴着它入土 我会变成孤魂野鬼在阴间…
If I'm not buried with it...my spirit will wander the netherworld.
够了，亲爱的
That's enough!
我不晓得
Oh,I don't know.
再让我看一次 当然，请看
-Let me see it. -Great. Okay,here.
好吧，跟你换
-All right,I'll do it.
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢
-Thank you.
你即将嫁给一个大好人
And you are about to marry a wonderful man.
我要娶一个死人
Hey,I'm marrying a dead woman!
兄弟们？
Guys?
我有大事要宣布，兄弟们？
I've got something important to tell you.Guys?
兄弟们？兄弟们？
Guys?Guys?
我要跟莫妮卡求婚了
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我们应该对他中止冷落
I think we gotta end the freeze-out.
等等，你是来真的？
Wait. Is this for real?
对，戒指在这里
Yeah. Check out the ring.
天哪
Oh,my God!
这么说你俩真的是认真的？
So you two are really serious?
差不多
Yeah,pretty much.
你们要结婚了？
You're gonna get married?
我们要成为亲戚了，过来
We're gonna be brothers-in-law! Come here!
我们又可以当朋友了
And we're gonna be friends again.
什么？
What?
过去的事就别提了 好吧
-Water under the bridge! Forget it! -Okay.
我本来想等搞定再说
I was gonna wait till it was official,\r}
但我还是忍不住要告诉你们 因为你们是我的最好的朋友
but I had to tell you guys.You're my best friends.
我真不敢相信
-I can't believe this.
我也是 我本来还想问你有什么打算
-Me too.I was planning on having a conversation with you about your intentions.
我要哭了
I think I'm gonna cry.
别再哭了，拜托
Oh! No more crying!
我刚甩掉一个爱哭宝宝 小心我也甩了你
I just dumped one crybaby. I'll dump you too.
我要跟莫妮卡求婚
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我的天哪，我的天哪
Oh,my God!Oh,my God!
钱德，你们会好幸福
Oh,Chandler! You guys are gonna be so happy!
我知道
-I know.
面纸都死哪去了？
-Where's all the tissues?!
这是戒指
-Check out the ring.
真好，至少有1.5克拉
-Oh,nice. One and a half carat,easy.
菲比，钱德要跟莫妮卡求婚了
-Hey. -Hey,Phoebe.He's gonna ask Monica to marry him.
我知道，是我陪他去挑戒指的
-I helped pick out the ring.
你先告诉她？
You told her before you told us?
我在看戒指目录时被她撞见 你们能谅解吧？
She walked in while I was looking at brochures. You can understand that.
兄弟们？
Guys?
天哪，钱德选的戒指好美
God,that ring Chandler picked out was so beautiful.
你当然很懂，你买过一大堆
You should know. You've bought like a billion of them.
拿我的痛处开玩笑
Humor based on my pain.
有趣的是
You know what's funny?
你的老婆里只有我没拿到戒指
Of all of your wives,I'm the only one who never got a ring.
你很在意吗？
This a big issue for you?
不是，只不过如果能有我们结婚的纪念品 总是蛮好的
No,but it would have been nice to have a little memento...of our married time together.
而不要只有离婚证书和烂醉
Something other than the divorce papers and the hangover.
罗斯显然不会送你戒指
Ross is obviously not gonna get you a ring.
不过跟他要毛瑟枪好了，毛瑟枪
But ask for a musket. Ask for a musket!
你知道我们结婚时 少做了什么事？
When we were married,do you know what I never got?
上床
Sex.
没戒指当然没得做，你还敢提
Well,yeah. No ring,no sex. Big surprise.
送我毛瑟枪，一切好谈
Get me a musket and we'll talk.